Inês Simões

Software Engineer

linkedin.com/in/inescsim

ines.csim@gmail.com +351 935 889 881 +44 7761 824051

Portugal

For the past two years, I've worked as a full-stack JavaScript developer and also served as the tech lead on one of the team's squads. In this role, I helped build a product focused on retention. This involved leading two developers and collaborating with a Product Manager and a Product Designer to generate ideas for new features based on user research while ensuring technical feasibility.

I recently relocated from London to Portugal, and for my next role, I'm looking for a fully remote role where I would ideally have a similar position both writing code and managing or mentoring people, as I believe those are my strengths.

Work Experience



Full Stack Developer at GetAgent

London, United Kingdom

React \cdot Koa \cdot Figma \cdot MySQL \cdot Next.js \cdot Git \cdot Asana \cdot CustomerIO March 2021 to April 2023

- Maintained and improved the product as a Full Stack Developer.
- Led a team of two developers in building a new product, collaborating with the Product Manager and Product Designer to generate ideas for new features based on user research, while ensuring technical feasibility.
- · Made decisions on the architecture of new tasks.
- Performed final technical QA of teamwork and eventual release.
- Collaborated with other teams in the business (CRM, marketing, SEO, etc.).
- Provided mentorship and management to trainees and junior developers in order to improve their performance and productivity, as well as to assist with their career progression.



Product Lead for Ethics Monitor at Haplo

London, United Kingdom

JavaScript · Trello · Git May 2019 to January 2021

- Led the end-to-end development process for custom applications, from authentication setup to successful deployment, ensuring client satisfaction.
- Provided support to existing clients.
- Mentored a team member, resulting in improved skills and contributions to the product.
- Actively participated in weekly discussions on team challenges.



Full Stack Developer at HYP

Coimbra, Portugal

jQuery \cdot PostgreSQL \cdot Git \cdot Ruby on Rails \cdot JavaScript September 2018 to January 2019

- Collaborated with a team of developers and designers to create and launch BabyLoop, a successful platform for buying and selling used baby products.
- Implemented various website components, including search and product pages, for a seamless user experience.

- Built the payments process and invoice generation using SIBS API and InvoiceExpress API respectively.
- Configured email jobs within Rails' Active Jobs to streamline communication processes.
- Utilised Ruby on Rails API to develop an API consumed by the mobile app.
- Developed an admin back office using rails admin to efficiently manage platform content.

Full Stack Developer at OneSource

Coimbra, Portugal

ONESOURCE

 $HTML \cdot jQuery \cdot Ruby \cdot Git \cdot JavaScript \cdot CSS$ March 2017 to August 2018

- Developed a SketchUp extension in collaboration with civil engineers from the University of Coimbra to optimize building structures, using SketchUp's Ruby API.
- Acted as the lead developer on the project and managed meetings with clients while reviewing and merging code from the civil engineering team for seamless integration.
- Led the development of the app interface as well as backend functionality, including calculations, database interaction, and API calls.

Education History



Bachelor's Degree, Informatics Engineering

University of Coimbra Year of Graduation: 2017

More about me

Interests

During my free time, I enjoy reading books, playing on my Nintendo Switch, and meeting friends to play board games.

At work I'm best at...

building relationships with colleagues. I take pride in being the go-to person when someone has a question, which has led to me naturally progressing toward mentorship and leadership roles.

I want to work for a company that...

values diversity and encourages healthy discussions on how things are going and what can be improved.